Register of the Carl Gershman papers, 1961-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
Carl Gershman papers
1961-1984
81124
Hoover Institution Archives
31 manuscript boxes (12.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, minutes, resolutions, and printed matter relating to the U.S. Mission to the U.N., socialist and radical movements in the U.S., and Social Democrats, U.S.A.
Gershman, Carl
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981, with incremental material received later.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1943 Born in New York City
1965 Graduated with a B.A. from Yale University
1965-1967 Volunteered as a Service to America (VISTA) worker, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
1968 Graduated with an M.Ed., Harvard University
1969-1974 Director of Research, Co-Chairman, and Executive Director, successively, of the Youth Committee for Peace and Democracy in the Middle East
1970-1974 Vice Chairman, Co-Chairman, and Chairman, successively, of the Young People's Socialist League
1971-1974 Director for the Youth Institute for Peace in the Middle East
1975-1980 Executive Director, Social Democrats, U.S.A.
1981-1984 Counselor to the U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations
1984- President of the National Endowment for Democracy
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, speeches and writings, minutes, resolutions, and printed matter relating to the U.S. Mission to the U.N., socialist, radical, and labor movements in the U.S., the Young People’s Socialist League, and Social Democrats, U.S.A. Includes an audio recording of a debate between Carl Gershman and M. Stanton Evans.
Social Democrats, U.S.A.; Young People's Socialist League of America.; Radicalism--United States.; Socialism--United States.; United States--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, printed matter, letters, and miscellany relating to the career of Carl Gershman, unarranged.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1967-1974 (Boxes 1-3)
  Typescript or printed copies of speeches and writings by Carl Gershman, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - "The A. Philip Randolph Institute: Putting Progressive Ideas into Practice" (co-author with Norman Hill), undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - "America's Stake in Israel's Security,", undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - "An Appeal by Jewish Youth to Defeat Bella Abzug" (co-author with others), 1972 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - "Between War and Peace: The Issues in the Middle East Conflict," Crossroads, 1971 June (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - "Black and White: Some Cause for Hope,", undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "The Black Panthers,", undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - "CORE: The Ultimate Absurdity,", undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - "CP: Unity 'Midst Diversity,'" New America, 1968 August 25 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "Cambodia Statement,", 1970 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - "Communists: What Are They Up To?," Pittsburgh Point, 1968 August 1 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - "Confusion in the Student Movement," Pittsburgh Point, 1968 October 24 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - "Conservatism + Isolationism = Fulbrightism," Crossroads, 1971 May (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - "Continuity, Evolution, and Community in the Thought of Charles S. Peirce" (college paper), 1967 December 14 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - "Countering Anti-Israel Propaganda on the Campus,", 1970 January 31 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - "Cultural Factors in Cognitive Growth" (college paper), 1967 December 18 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - "Currents of Reform in the Building Trades,", undated (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - "Decentralization: A Solution?" (college paper), 1967 January 15 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - "The Dilemma Facing Higher Education,", undated (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - "Down with SNCC: Up(?) with the Panthers," Pittsburgh Point, 1968 September 19 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - "Education Is Still for the Elite,", undated (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - "Egypt and Russia: A Tremor but Not a Quake,", undated (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - "An Encounter with the American Press in Israel," American Zionist, 1972 May (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - "The Failure of the Fedayeen,", undated (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - "Fulbright's 'Humbuggery'" [American Jewish], Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971 May 21 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - "Game of the Name," Village Voice (letter to the editor), 1972 January 20 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - "George Ball's Policy," Newsweek (letter to the editor), 1972 July 17 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - "Gunter Grass: Our Contemporary Prophet,", undated (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - "Henry Clay Frick" (college paper), undated (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - "Isolation of the New Left," Nation, 1969 May 26 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - "Israel and American Labor: An Enduring Friendship,", undated (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - "Israel and the Big Power Triangle" [American Jewish], Congress Bi-Weekly, 1972 January 14 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - "Israel and the Elections,", 1972 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - "Israel and Vietnam: A Shaky Comparison,", undated (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - "Israel: The New Left Is Not The Enemy," Sh'ma, 1971 October 22 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - "Israel's Fate," Alternative, 1974 January (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - "The Issues in the Jarring Talks: 'Peace on the Cheap'" [American Jewish], Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971 April 30 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - "Jackson and the Jews," University [of Texas] Jewish Voice, 1972 January 23 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - "Jackson: 'Talking to the Common People,'" ADA World, 1972 February (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - "Jewish Youth and the New Left,", undated (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - "Jews and Blacks: The Need for Unity," Keeping Posted, 1971 February (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - "The Jews and the Elections," American Zionist, 1972 September (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - "The Jews and the Left,", undated (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - "Labor and the Elections,", 1972 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - "Labor's Stand on McGovern," New Leader, 1972 September 4 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - "The Lessons of the 1970 Elections" (co-author with Norman Hill) (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - "The Lessons of the Primaries,", 1970 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Letter to the editor, Commentary, 1970 January 14 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Letter to the editor, New Republic, 1969 March 27 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Review of Books, 1968 October 1 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1969 May 5 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1970 January 12 (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1970 May 20 (Box-folder 1: 53)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1970 August 26 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1973 September 9 (Box-folder 1: 55)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times Magazine, 1969 June 24 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Letter to the editor, Wall Street Journal, 1969 May 21 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - "Maple Lodge Camp: A Success Story," Pittsburgh Point, 1967 July 13 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "The Middle East,", undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "The New Face of Anti-Zionism," American Zionist, 1971 December (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "New Ideology in the New Left," Pittsburgh Point, 1968 September 5 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "The New Left in the Nixon Era," Pittsburgh Point, 1969 January 2 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "The New Left, Israel, and Jewish Youth," Workmen's Circle Call, 1971 July (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "A New Look at Marx" (review of David McLellan, Karl Marx: His Life and Thought), undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "New Stirrings among Young People,", undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "The New YPSL,", 1973 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - "The 1970 Elections" (co-author with Norman Hill), 1970 September (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - "Nixon's Strategy and the Liberal Dilemma,", undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - "The Op. Ed. Page: Both Ends against the Middle,", undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - "The Origins of 'Self-Determination,'", undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - "Pacification Not School Reform at Heart of Lindsay's Strategy," New America, 1968 November 15 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - "The Panacea of a Palestinian State,", undated (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - "A Perspective on Jewish Youth," ADL Bulletin, 1972 May (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - "Pitfalls of a Palestine State," New Leader, 1970 November 2 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - "The Plight of Soviet Dissidents,", undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - "Politics in the Cambridge Schools" (college paper), 1968 April 30 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - "The Politics of Education," Pittsburgh Point (review of Peter Schrag, Village School Downtown), 1967 September 7 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - "The Problem of Black Nationalism" (review of Theodore Draper, The Rediscovery of Black Nationalism, Addison Gayle, Jr., The Black Situation, and Arnold Schuchter, Reparations), undated (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - "Problem of the Aged,", 1970 May (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - "A Problem for American Youth,", undated (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "Race and Other Matters,", undated (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - "A Radical Defense of Israel,", undated (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - "The Real Threat to Israel,", undated (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - "Republican Contradictions,", undated (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Review of David Caute, The Fellow Travellers: A Postscript to the Englightenment, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Review of Mordecai S. Chertoff, ed., The New Left and the Jews, Jewish Frontier, 1971 November (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Review of Kirkpatrick Sale, SDS, undated (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - "Review of the Press,", undated (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - "Revising Orwell and Solzhenitsyn," Social Democrat, 1973 Fall (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - "Rowland Evans' Complaint,", undated (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - "SDS, or the New Thermidor," Pittsburgh Point, 1969 June 5 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - "Senator Henry M. Jackson: Israel's Dependable Friend,", undated (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - "Senator Jackson and the Jews," American Zionist, 1972 February (Box-folder 2: 36)
  - "A Short History of SDS,", undated (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - "Some Thoughts on YPSL and the American Working Class,", undated (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - "The Soviet Dissidents and the West,", undated (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - "Soviet Jews as Political Hostages: An Interpretation" [American Jewish], Congress Bi-Weekly, 1970 October 23 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Speech, Board of Governors, B'nai B'rith, 1971 January 9 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - "The State of the Anti-Israel Left" [American Jewish], Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971 January 22 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - "The State of the Democrats,", 1972 (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - "A Study of Negro Separatism," Dialogue (review of Theodore Draper, The Rediscovery of Black Nationalism), 1971 (Box-folder 2: 44)
  - "Teachers' Values: An Overview and a Study" (college paper), 1968 May 15 (Box-folder 2: 45)
  - "Terror and Democracy," Workmen's Circle Call, 1972 November-December (Box-folder 2: 46)
  - "Tom Mboya's Death: A Loss to His People and to the World,", undated (Box-folder 2: 47)
  - "The UFT in Crisis" (college paper), 1968 May 22 (Box-folder 2: 48)
  - Untitled, undated (Box-folder 2: 49)
  - "Vietnam War Kills Pgh. Poverty War Gains,", undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Wallace, 'the White Hope,' Exploits Fear," New America, 1968 September 30 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "Which Way American Jewry?,", 1972 April 18 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "Who Teaches American Chidren?" (college paper), undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Why I'm for Scoop Jackson, Coalition Politics, Social Justice and Peace (and against Know-Nothingism),", 1972 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "The YPSL after Five Years,", 1971 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "Young Radicals Seek their Place in History," Pittsburgh Point, 1967 February 2 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "Young Workers and the Unions,", undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "Youth and Group Identity: Toward Dialogue between Jewish and Non-Jewish Youth,", undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - "Youth and Israel,", undated (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - "Youth and Politics,", undated (Box-folder 3: 11)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1962-1978 (Boxes 3-14)
  Writings, letters, minutes, reports, resolutions, statements, press releases, memoranda, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Affirmative action programs (see: Afro-Americans)
  - Africa (see also: Slavery; South Africa; Sudan)
    - General, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 3: 12)
      Writings, memoranda, reports, press releases, and bulletins.
    - Clippings, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - Printed matter, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Afro-Americans (see also: Black Panther Party; Rustin, Bayard)
    - General, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 3: 15)
      Writings, notes, letters, memoranda, and press releases.
    - Clippings, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Printed matter, 1963-1975 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - American Federation of Teachers (see: Shanker, Albert)
  - Arab countries - relations (general) with Africa (see: Africa)
  - Asia, clippings, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Australia (see: Socialism in Australia)
  - Black Panther Party, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 4: 4-5)
    Clippings, printed matter, notes, memoranda, press releases, and interview transcript.
  - Blacks - relations with Jews (see: Afro-Americans)
  - Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America, newspaper issues, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Brown, Sam, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    Letters, press releases, and clippings.
  - Evans, Rowland, and Robert Novak, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    Newspaper columns and clippings.
  - Germany, West (see: Socialism in West Germany)
  - Harrington, Michael (see: Social Democrats, U.S.A.; Socialist Party, U.S.A.)
  - Institute for Policy Studies, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 5: 4-5)
    Memoranda, press releases, printed matter, clippings, and issuances of the Institute for Policy Studies.
  - Ireland, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Pamphlets, leafets, printed matter, and notes.
  - Italy (see: Socialism in Italy)
  - Jackson, Henry M.
    - General, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5: 7)
      Press releases, writings, notes, letters, and memoranda.
    - Clippings, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Printed matter, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Speeches and writings by Henry M. Jackson
      - General, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 6: 1)
        Printed and mimeographed copies.
      - Typescripts, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Jews - relations with Blacks (see: Afro-Americans)
  - Jews in Russia, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    Clippings, printed matter, press releases, leaflets, and statement.
  - Military service - compulsory, clippings, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Near East (see also: Slavery), 1969-1977 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    Letters, notes, speeches, writings, and printed matter.
  - Novak, Robert (see: Evans, Rowland, and Robert Novak)
  - Radicalism - U.S. (see also: Black Panther Party; Students for a Democratic Society)
    - General, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 6: 6)
      Notes, memoranda, leaflets, and writings.
    - Clippings, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
    - Issuances of radical organizations, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
    - Printed matter, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Printed matter, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Randolph, A. Philip (see: Rustin, Bayard)
  - Russia (see: Jews in Russia)
  - Rustin, Bayard
    - General, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
      Letters, notes, memoranda, speeches, writings, and printed matter.
    - Speeches and writings by Bayard Rustin
      - Mimeographed copies, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - Printed copies, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - Typescripts, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Shanker, Albert
    - General, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      Clippings, printed matter, memorandum, and study.
    - Speeches and writings by Albert Shanker
      - Printed copies, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Typescripts, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Slavery, 1966-1974 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    Pamphlets, printed matter, reports, and letter.
  - Social Democrats, U.S.A. (see also: Socialist Party, U.S.A.; Young People's Socialist League)
    - Undated notes, leaflets, and statements (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Minutes, reports, statements, letters, press releases, writings, lists, leaflets, newsletters, pamphlet, clippings, and printed matter, 1973 (Box-folder 9: 7-8)
    - Lists, notes, and memoranda, 1974 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Agenda, list, and financial report, 1975 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Socialism in Australia, campaign manual, 1976 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Socialism in Italy, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    Serial issues, campaign literature, and printed reports.
  - Socialism in Spain, serial issues, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Socialism in West Germany, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 10: 3-5)
    Serial issues, pamphlets, brochures, and other printed matter.
  - Socialist Party, U.S.A. (see also: Social Democrats, U.S.A.; Young People's Socialist League)
    - Undated notes, lists, resolutions, statements, press releases, writings, clippings, and leaflets (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Constitution, statement, leaflet, and clippings, 1968 (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Notes, statements, reports, clippings, and printed matter, 1969 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Correspondence, writings, reports, resolutions, press releases, leaflets, discussion bulletins, clippings, and printed matter, 1970 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Minutes, reports, resolutions, statements, discussion bulletins, press releases, newsletters, letters, memoranda, clippings, and printed matter, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 2-3)
    - Minutes, reports, resolutions, statements, constitution, writings, newsletters, press releases, printed matter, clippings, and printed matter, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 4-5)
  - South Africa, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 11: 6)
    Clippings, pamphlets, and newsletters.
  - Spain (see: Socialism in Spain)
  - Students for a Democratic Society
    - General, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 11: 7)
      Writings, letters, clippings, and printed matter.
    - Issuances of the Students for a Democratic Society
      - General, 1964 (Box-folder 12: 1)
        Leaflets, bulletins, and statements.
      - New Left Notes, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 12: 2)
      - SDS Bulletin, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 12: 3-4)
  - Sudan, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    Writings and clippings.
  - U.S. - economic conditions, 1963-1977 (Box-folder 12: 6-7)
    Clippings, serial issues, pamphlets, statements, and printed matter.
  - U.S. - politics and government, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    Clippings, writings, notes, and printed matter.
  - World politics, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    Notes, pamphlets, and printed matter.
  - Young People's Socialist League (see also: Social Democrats, U.S.A.; Socialist Party, U.S.A.)
    - Undated writings, notes, memoranda, questionnaires, resolutions, and leaflets (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Letters, memoranda, financial records, and printed resolution, 1966 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Writings, letters, financial records, lists, and notes, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Letters, notes, lists, and financial records, 1968 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Minutes, discussion bulletins, reports, resolutions, statements, letters, speech, and leaflets, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 6-7)
    - Minutes, correspondence, discussion bulletin, reports, resolutions, memoranda, lists, and printed matter, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Minutes, discussion bulletins, letters, memoranda, resolutions, statements, notes, financial records, and clippings, 1971 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
    - Minutes, discussion bulletins, letters, memoranda, resolutions, statement, notes, financial records, newsletters, writings, and printed matter, 1972 (Box-folder 14: 3-4)
    - Minutes, discussion bulletins, letters, memoranda, resolutions, statements, notes, financial records, newsletters, and clippings, 1973 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Minutes, letters, memoranda, resolutions, statements, notes, financial records, newsletters, and clippings, 1974 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Minutes, statements, letters, and printed matter, 1975 (Box-folder 14: 7)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1961-1984 (Boxes 15-31)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1969-1983 (Boxes 15-16)
    - Letters neither to nor from Carl Gershman, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - General, 1969-1983
      - A-L, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 15: 3)
      - M-Z, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Adams, Jim, 1976 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Avineri, Shlomo, 1973 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Bardacke, Gregory, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Bardacke, Judy, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Barish, Rabbi Louis, 1972 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Baum, Phil, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - Borowitz, Eugene B., 1971 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Brown, Irving, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 12)
    - Bruzonsky, Mark A., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    - Clark, Joseph, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 14)
    - Cole, Donald F., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 15: 15)
    - Cooper, Elias, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 15: 16)
    - Cukor, Gregory, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - Elliott, Stuart C., 1974 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    - Feldman, Paul, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    - Fenyvesi, Charles, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 15: 20)
    - Furman, Norman, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 21)
    - Godson, Christine, 1974 (Box-folder 15: 22)
    - Gould, David J., 1970 (Box-folder 15: 23)
    - Green, Max, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15: 24)
    - Griffin, Gary, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 25)
    - Higman, Howard, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 26)
    - Jennings, Paul, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15: 27)
    - Kahn, Tom, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 15: 28)
    - Kaplan, Kivie, 1970 (Box-folder 15: 29)
    - Katz, Shlomo, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 30)
    - Kluntznick, Philip, 1971 (Box-folder 15: 31)
    - Laqueur, Walter, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Leopold, Louis, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Levine, Charley, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Lookstein, Haskel, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Lovestone, Jay, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Marinsky, Deborah, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - Moss, Israel, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - Muravchik, Josh, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - Peretz, Martin, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - Podhoretz, Norman, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - Poster, Herbert, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 16: 12)
    - Ra'anan, Uri, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    - Resnick, Harris, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - Roche, John, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 16: 15)
    - Rustin, Bayard, 1974 (Box-folder 16: 16)
    - Saguy, Eli, 1973 (Box-folder 16: 17)
    - Samuel, Edith, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 16: 18)
    - Sanders, Ronald, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 19)
    - Shanker, Albert, 1980 (Box-folder 16: 20)
    - Shore, Sarah, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 16: 21)
    - Smith Richardson Foundation, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 16: 22)
    - Stern, William, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 16: 23)
    - Suall, Joan, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 16: 24)
    - Weisberg, Sam, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 25)
    - Wouk, Herman, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 16: 26)
    - Zung, Barbara, 1971 (Box-folder 16: 27)
    - Letters to the editor, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 16: 28)
    - Unidentified, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 16: 29)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1969-1980 (Boxes 16-17)
    Arrangement Statement
    Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically thereunder.
    - "American Youth and the Middle East,", 1970 (Box-folder 16: 30)
    - "The Panacea of a Palestinian State,", 1970 (Box-folder 16: 31)